# **DEEPAK KUMAR**

**Profile** 

(+91) 7022409865, (+91) 8052211414 dk66186@gmail.com LinkedIn GitHub

#### **SUMMARY:**

**Full Stack Developer** with over two years of IT experience. Versatile, bilingual professional with **MEAN Stack** and **J2EE** projects ranging in size from open source projects to full scale multi-million dollar high profile corporate construction projects. Ability to provide efficient solutions to real life problems and develop restful web services for operational intelligence.

## **SOFTWARE EXPERIENCE:**

Ola Cabs 11/2017 – Present

Software Development Engineer (2 months)

Wipro Technologies Ltd. 07/2015 – 10/2017

Project Engineer (2 years 4 months)

#### **EDUCATION:**

# Indian Institute of Technology (BHU), Varanasi

2011-2015

• B. Tech in Electrical Engineering (Cumulative CGPA: 8.09 on absolute scale)

#### **SKILLS AND INTERESTS:**

- **Technical Skills**: Core Java, JavaScript, Node.js, Angular.js, Express.js, jQuery, Servlets, Spring MVC, Hibernate, JDBC, JSP
- Familiar Technologies: Angular Material Design, Document Extraction, HTML, HTML5, CSS, CSS3, D3.js, Bootstrap, Natural Language Processing, Passport.js, Junit, Socket.io, Meteor.js, Ruby on rails
- Databases: MongoDB, SQL
- Areas of Interest: Data Structure and Algorithms.

# **PROJECT EXPERIENCE:**

Project 1: Currently working as part of team responsible for end to end application development of Ola Corporate.

[Team Size: 10] 11/2017 – current

Project 2: Developed full featured UI of Chatbot of Wipro HOLMES using meteor.js framework.

[Team Size: 4] 06/2017 – 10/2017

Project 3: Developed complete UI of a cognitive AI tool for a US title insurance company as part of client project.

[Team Size: 10] 11/2016 – 05/2017

• The UI has feature of both folder and file uploading along with save and update option for finding final vesting. It has a beautiful timeline feature along with various d3 graphs and table visualizations.

Project 4: Developed a tool for client that takes pdf, word, rtf documents as input and generates structured XML as output. [Team Size: 6] 07/2016 – 10/2016

- The tool extracts **entities** like front matter, paragraph, subparagraph, headers, footnotes etc. from unstructured data (pdf, word) and then fill them in their respective tags in **xml** format.
- Enhanced Apache pdf2html API **source code** to read bold, italic and underline information as well as to **annotate** entities in document itself.

Project 5: Developed a **Chat Application** that allows users to share text messages, photos, smileys and chat in groups. [**Team Size: 2**] **GitHub Snapshots 05/2016 – 07/2016** 

Project 6: Developed a web based Media Player that plays local audio and video files in browser.

**GitHub Snapshots** 

05/2016 - 06/2016

Project 7: Developed an Open Source product named Tattva, which aggregates the logs from different sources and has predefined watch lists and visualizations based on which automated actions can be triggered. It helps in Operational Intelligence. [Team Size: 6] 10/2015 – 05/2016

• This application does **Real Time** log data analysis and helps in **complex event processing.** It turns machine data into valuable insights. **GitHub Snapshots** 

**Project 8:** Developed an **Online Cab Booking System** using Spring MVC.

08/2015 - 10/2015

**GitHub Snapshots** 

## **ACHIEVEMENTS / EXTRA CURRICULAR ACTIVITIES:**

- Did Immersive Full MEAN Stack Training in Stack route (NIIT CENTRE), Bangalore as a part of Wipro Digital Academy Training Program.
- Participation in ALL INDIA PAPER PRESENTATION CONTEST in first year (2011).
- Received scholarship for class 11th and 12th from school.
- Received a cash award of Rs 20,000 from Bihar state govt for securing 95% marks in class 10.
- Received 'Pratibha Samman' award from SBI Patna in 2011

## **PERSONAL INFORMATION:**

• Father: Shambhu Prasad

Nationality: IndianLanguages: English, Hindi

• Github: https://github.com/deepak1745

Mother: Usha KumariDate of Birth: 23/02/1993

Hobbies: Music, Cricket, Football, Piano